<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>王超 Chao Wang | Networked Cyber-Physical Systems Lab - National Taiwan Normal University - Deptartment of Computer Science and Information Engineering</title>
    <link>https://wangc86.github.io/authors/cw/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wangc86.github.io/authors/cw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>王超 Chao Wang</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wangc86.github.io/authors/cw/avatar_hu436b270f6ba881d20a85299fe36b3d72_74906_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>王超 Chao Wang</title>
      <link>https://wangc86.github.io/authors/cw/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chain Bible Verse Reference</title>
      <link>https://wangc86.github.io/cr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangc86.github.io/cr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, between the pages of an old NKJV Bible distributed by The Gideons International, I came across a series of hand-written verse references, with a final remark saying that &amp;ldquo;Now that you have read God&amp;rsquo;s plan of salvation, it is my prayer that you will understand and accept Jesus as your Saviour.&amp;rdquo; Those verses now I copied down here, in the hope that they would help the readers, too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:23&lt;br&gt;
Romans 6:23&lt;br&gt;
Ephesians 2:8-9&lt;br&gt;
Luke 18:13&lt;br&gt;
John 3:16-17&lt;br&gt;
1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;br&gt;
Romans 10:9-10&lt;br&gt;
2 Corinthians 6:2&lt;br&gt;
Acts 8:35-39&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are translations from the KJV Bible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Romans 3:23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the wages of sin is death; but the gift of God is eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Romans 6:23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For by grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: it is the gift of God: not of works, lest any man should boast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Ephesians 2:8-9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the publican, standing afar off, would not lift up so much as his eyes unto heaven, but smote upon his breast, saying, God be merciful to me a sinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Luke 18:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life. For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;John 3:16-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There hath no temptation taken you but such as is common to man: but God is faithful, who will not suffer you to be tempted above that ye are able; but will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved. For with the heart man believeth unto righteousness; and with the mouth confession is made unto salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Romans 10:9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For he saith, I have heard thee in a time accepted, and in the day of salvation have I succoured thee: behold, now is the accepted time; behold, now is the day of salvation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;2 Corinthians 6:2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Philip opened his mouth, and began at the same scripture, and preached unto him Jesus. And as they went on their way, they came unto a certain water: and the eunuch said, See, here is water; what doth hinder me to be baptized? And Philip said, If thou believest with all thine heart, thou mayest. And he answered and said, I believe that Jesus Christ is the Son of God. And he commanded the chariot to stand still: and they went down both into the water, both Philip and the eunuch; and he baptized him. And when they were come up out of the water, the Spirit of the Lord caught away Philip, that the eunuch saw him no more: and he went on his way rejoicing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Acts 8:35-39&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
